# **DEEPA LAKSHMI**

Chennai, India | P: +91 9600834554 | deepa16lakshmi@gmail.com| www.linkedin.com/in/deepa16

## **SUMMARY**

Experienced QA automation engineer with 7+ years of experience and a passion for automation. Proven ability to develop and implement test plans, scripts, and tools that improve the quality of software products. Possesses excellent problem-solving skills and the ability to work effectively in a team environment.

## **EXPERIENCE**

# Hippo video - Chennai, India

Sep 2017 – Present

Senior QA Automation Engineer

- Taking full responsibility for the project's success with a maximum role that involves quality and test advocacy, test plan, test scenario, test case review, writing scripts, and the resolution of issues that impede the testing effort.
- Being accountable for the test automation projects; mentoring, releasing builds, and providing leadership to the QA team.
- Expertise in performing functional testing, integration testing, regression testing, smoke testing, sanity testing, and UAT.
- Increased product quality and reduced manual testing by designing and implementing automation test cases using Selenium WebDriver, Mocha Js, TestNG, TestSigma, and Karate.
- Involved in preparing and reviewing test scenarios and ensuring 100% test coverage across modules and platforms.
- Used Mochawesome reporter and Testsigma to get automation reports on a daily basis and integrated with the Google Chat bot.
- Utilized Puppeteer to develop automated test scripts and improve testing efficiency.
- Monitoring the test results, leaking defects, root cause analysis, and implementing the steps required for improving the process.
- Participated in daily stand-up meetings, which ensured that the team members were aware of current progress and upcoming milestones, improved morale and boosted productivity.
- Worked on API testing using Postman, Mesh Dynamics and Load testing using JMeter and Gatling.
- Developed test cases and scripts, and created virtual users in Gatling for Load, Stress and Performance Testing of the application.

## Zarget - Chennai, India

#### QA Automation Engineer

Aug 2016 - Aug 2017

- Worked single-handedly on complete UI Automation for the following CRO tools from scratch to finish.
- Experience with automation tools like Selenium WebDriver with Java, TestNG, Maven and Jenkins for testing web-based applications.
- Created Automation script that executes the test cases and reports the result in Google Spreadsheet.
- Designed custom report generation that displays the status of the test cases.

- Implemented TestNG unit testing framework for the functionality test and used all annotations in TestNG effectively.
- Responsible for developing the scripts to support Jenkins (continuous Integration) of the scripts with the build server.
- Performed Functional, Smoke, Usability, Integration and Regression Testing.

## BIX Private Limited - Chennai, India

Oct 2015 - July 2016

Associate Software Quality Assurance Engineer

- Performed manual testing on web-based, executing test cases and documenting defects.
- Designed and executed automated test scripts using Selenium WebDriver, reducing test execution time and increasing overall test coverage.
- Worked with cross-functional teams to implement automation tools like Selenium in their product.
- Identified, documented, and tracked software defects using bug tracking tools (e.g., JIRA), and collaborated with developers to facilitate timely resolutions.

#### Technical Intern

- Gained exposure to the software development life cycle (SDLC) and participated in Agile development processes.
- Actively engaged in learning and exploring automation testing tools like Selenium.
- Assisted in manual testing efforts by executing test cases, documenting results, and identifying and reporting software defects.

#### SKILLS

Programming: Core Java, Javascript

Automation Tools Front End: Test Sigma, Selenium WebDriver, Selenium IDE, QTP, TestNG, Mocha

JS, Puppeteer

Automation Tools Back End: Karate

Performance Testing Tools: Jmeter, Gatling

Project Management Tools: Jira, Zoho Projects, Fresh Release, Trello

Tools: Postman, Maven, VS Code, Eclipse, Git, TestRail

**Database:** Postgres

CI/CD: Jenkin

## **EDUCATION**

**SRM - Easwari Engineering College, Anna University – Chennai, India** *July 2011 – May 2015*Bachelor of Engineering, Information Technology; Cumulative GPA: 8.0/10